Guide to the Frederick Law Olmsted architectural drawings and plans, 1877-1927
Olmsted, Frederick Law architectural drawings and plans, 1877-1927
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Frederick Law Olmsted architectural drawings and plans, 1877-1927.
462
Frederick Law Olmsted 1822-1903.
1 map case drawer; 1 folder.
Drawings, maps, negatives, manuscripts, reports, brochures.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Copies of sketches, planting plans, maps, and general plans of gardens, parks, private estates, and portions of cities with material from various firms. Also "Ancestral Register of Frederick Law Olmsted, c. 1592-1878," and reports and brochures dealing with Olmsted.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Copies of sketches, planting plans, maps, and general plans of gardens, parks, private estates, and portions of cities in Chicago, Boston, Long Island, Massachusetts, New York, Pennsylvania, and other places, with material from various firms, including Olmsted, Olmsted, and Eliot; F. L. Olmsted and Co.; F. L. and J. C. Olmsted; and Olmsted Brothers - Landscape Architects, run by Frederick Law Olmsted, Jr. and John Charles Olmsted;"Ancestral Register of Frederick Law Olmsted, c. 1592-1878," and reports and brochures dealing with Olmsted.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Olmsted, Frederick Law,1822-1903.; Olmsted, Frederick Law,; Olmsted, John Charles.; F. L. and J. C. Olmsted.; F. L. Olmsted and Co.; Olmsted and Co.; Olmsted, Olmsted, and Eliot.
Subjects:
Landscape architecture.
Form and Genre Terms:
Architectural drawings.; Genealogies.; Maps.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Drawings are filed in folders by state as follows:
Geographical Location
Folder Number
California
1
Connecticut
7
Florida
1
Illinois
8
Kentucky
2
Maine
1
Maryland
1
Massachusetts
5
Mount Royal
1
New Jersey
3
New York
4
Ohio
2
Pennsylvania
6
Rhode Island
3
Washington, D.C.
1
Wisconsin
1
SERIES LIST
Series I. Olmsted Collection of Drawings
Series II. F. L. Olmsted Co.
Series III. F. L. J. C. Olmsted
Series IV. Olmsted, Olmsted Eliot
Series V. Olmsted Brothers - Landscape Architects
Series VI. Oversize Drawings
Series VII. Pamphlets
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Olmsted Collection of Drawings (Listed by City)
  - Albany
    - Washington Park, 1891 (Folder 4)
      Most likely not by F. L. Olmsted
  - Baltimore
    - Roland Park, 1901 (Folder 1)
    - The Sudbrook Co., 1899 (Folder 1)
  - Berkeley, California
    - Duncan McDuffie, 1914 (Folder 1)
  - Boston
    - Blue Hills Reservation (Folder 5)
    - Charlesbank, 1892 (Folder 5)
    - Charles River Reservation, 1895 (Folder 5)
    - Jamaica Park, 1892 (Folder 5)
    - Little Nahant (Folder 5)
    - Marine Park, 1889 1891 (Folder 5)
    - Marine Park, 1899 (Folder 5)
    - Middlesex Fells Parkway, 1895 (Folder 5)
    - Middlesex Fells Reservation (Folder 5)
    - Mystic Valley Parkway, 1895 (Folder 5)
    - Neponset River, 1899 (Folder 5)
    - Newton Boulevard Syndicate, 1894 (Folder 5)
    - Parkway: Revere Beach, 1892 (Folder 5)
    - Parkway: Jamaica Park to Frankl Park, 1892 (Folder 5)
    - Parkway: Muddy River Gatehouse Jamaica Park, 1892 (Folder 5)
    - Parkway: Middlesex Fells, 1884 (Folder 5)
    - ____ Roxbury Park, 1884 (Folder 5)
  - Brookline, Mass.
    - Estate of Edward S. Philbrick, 1889 (Folder 5)
  - Buffalo
    - South Park, 1884 (1894?) (Folder 4)
  - Cambridge, Mass.
    - Harvard Arboretum, 1880 (Folder 5)
  - Campbell Park, Millburn, N.J.
    - Downing Vaux (Folder 3)
  - Chicago, Ill.
    (Other Parks of Chicago without name of landscape architect in drawer marked Landscape Architects - General)
    - Calumet Park, 1904 (Folder 8)
    - Mark White Square, 1904 (Folder 8)
    - Palmer Park, 1904 (Folder 8)
    - Russell Square, 1904 (Folder 8)
    - Union Park, 1912 (Folder 8)
    - West Park, 1914 (Folder 8)
    - Washington Park, 1905 (Folder 8)
    - Grant Park, 1903 (Folder 8)
    - Lincoln Park, 1915 (Folder 8)
    - Jackson Park, 1905 (Folder 8)
    - Humbolt Park, 1912 (Folder 8)
    - Garfield Park, 1912 (Folder 8)
  - Cold Harbor Springs, Long Island, N.Y.
    - Dr. Walter James Cemetary Lot, 1923 (Folder 4)
  - Craig Colony, Sonyea, N.Y., 1889 (Folder 4)
  - East Aurora, 1906 (Folder 4)
  - Elmhurst, Long Island, N.Y.
    - Jackson Heights Garden Apartments, Inc., 1923 (Folder 4)
  - Essex County, N.J., 1900-1902
    - Branch Brook Park, 1901 (Folder 3)
  - Fox Meadow, Hartsdale, N.Y.
    - Property of C. Butler, 1900 (Folder 4)
  - Glen Cove, Long Island, N.Y.
    - J. E. Aldred - house and gardens, 1916 (Folder 4)
    - G. F. Baker, Jr., 1923 (Folder 4)
  - Hartford
    - Pope Park, 1898 (Folder 7)
    - Goodwin Park, 1900 (Folder 7)
    - Keney Park, 1898 (Folder 7)
  - Hills Dales, Montgomery Co., Ohio
    - C. E. Steffey, 1921 (Folder 2)
  - Hingham, Mass.
    - Property John Brewer, 1890 (Folder 5)
  - Louisville
    - Chickasaw Park, 1923 (Folder 2)
    - Logan Place, 1892 (Folder 2)
  - Lynn, Mass.
    - Meadow Park, 1920 (Folder 5)
  - Milwaukee
    - West Park, 1885 (Folder 1)
    - Lake Park, 1885 (Folder 1)
  - Mount Holyoke College, South Hadley, Mass., 1900 (Folder 5)
  - Mount Royal, 1877 (Folder 5)
  - Newark, N.J.
    - Southern Parkway, 1923 (Folder 3)
  - Newport, R.I.
    - Southern Harbor, 1897 (Folder 3)
  - Newton, Mass.
    - L. D. Towle, 1920 (Folder 5)
  - New York, N.Y.
    - Bay Ridge Park, 1895 (Folder 4)
    - Borough of the Bronx (Folder 4)
    - Bryn Mawr - William Mitchell Estate, Yonkers, N.Y., 1890 (Folder 4)
    - Central Park (Folder 4)
    - Prospect Park, 1901 (Folder 4)
  - Rochester
    - Seneca Park, 1893 (Folder 4)
  - Philadelphia
    - Fairmount Park, 1910 (Folder 6)
  - Portland, Maine (Folder 1)
  - Providence
    - Oaklands Homestead Plat - Estate of Sarah B. Heaton, 1894 (Folder 3)
  - Vandergrift, Westmoreland County, Pa., 1897 (Folder 6)
  - Washington, D.C.
    - Catholic University of America, 1927 (Folder 1)
  - Westerly, R.I.
    - W. Ward, 1921 (Folder 3)
  - Wilkes-Barre, Pa.
    - F. M. Kirby Park, 1922 (Folder 6)
  - Wongpenanit, Montauk, Ill.
    - General Plan - Property of F. S. M. Benson, 1897 (Folder 8)
  - Wyomissing, Pa.
    - E. R. Meinig, 1922 (Folder 6)
  - Maps
    - Cincinnati (Folder 2)
    - France
    - Maryland (Folder 1)
    - New York (Folder 1)
    - Pennsylvania (Folder 6)
  - Prefecture du Department de la Seine - Plan d'amenagement et d'extension de Paris, 1919
- Series II. F. L. Olmsted Co.
  - Proposition as to a Public Ground to Include the Harvard Arboretum (also another copy added July 17, 1974), Nov. 1880 (Folder 5)
  - General Plan for Sudbrook. The Property of The Sudbrook Co. of Baltimore, Maryland, Aug. 24, 1889 (Folder 1)
  - General Plan for the Subdivision into Roads and Building Sites of the William Mitchell Estate - Bryn Mawr, Yonkers, New York, Oct. 1890 (Folder 4)
  - General Plan for the Subdivision of Planter's Hill and World's End, Hingham, Mass. The Property of John R. Brewer Esq., 1890 (Folder 5)
  - Preliminary Plan of Jamaica Park, Dec. 1892 (Folder 5)
  - Plan of the Parkway Between Muddy River Gate House and Jamaica Park, Dec. 1892 (Folder 5)
  - Plan of the Parkway From Jamaica Park to Franklin Park, Dec. 1892 (Folder 5)
  - Plan of the Charlesbank, Dec. 1892 (Folder 5)
  - Plan of Logan Place, Louisville, 1892 (Folder 2)
  - General Plan for Seneca Park, Rochester, 1893 (Folder 4)
  - Plan of the Arnold Arboretum, showing progress of the work, and tree planting drawing, Oct. 31, 1887 (Folder 5)
- Series III. F. L. J. C. Olmsted
  - Plan for the Subdivision of the Estate of Edward S. Philbrick, Brookline, Mass., May 22, 1889 (Folder 5)
  - Revised Preliminary Plan of Wood Island Park, Boston, July 19, 1889 (Folder 5)
  - Revised Study of a Plan for Marine Park, Boston, Dec. 1889 (Folder 5)
  - Marine Park - Plan of Proposed Aquarial Gardens, Feb. 1891 (Folder 5)
  - General Plan for the Town of Vandergrift, Westmoreland Co., Pennsylvania, July 1897 (Folder 6)
  - General Plan for Subdivision of Wompenanit, Montauk, Long Island - Property of Frank Sherman Benson May Benson, Dec. 1897 (Folder 4)
- Series IV. Olmsted, Olmsted, Eliot
  - General Plan for Subdividing into Roads and Building Lots the Property of Newton Boulevard Syndicate (Boston), Blocks 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 10, 12 and of Robert R. Bishop, Blocks 6 7, Feb. 1894 (Folder 5)
  - Sketch Plan Showing the Existing Proposed Public Reservations upon the Banks of the Charles River Between Waltham Line and Craigie Bridge, Mar. 1894 (Folder 5)
  - Oaklands-Homestead Plat - General Plan for Subdivision of Estate of Sarah B. Eaton. Providence, Rhode Island., June 1894 (Folder 3)
  - General Plan of South Park, Buffalo, N.Y., Dec. 1894 (Folder 4)
  - General Plan of West Park (Buffalo?), January 1895 (Folder 4?)
  - General Plan of Lake Park (Buffalo?), Jan. 1895 (Folder 4?)
  - Mystic Valley Parkway (Boston) - General Plan, Nov. 1895 (Folder 5)
  - Middlesex Fells Parkway (Boston) - General Plan, Nov. 1895 (Folder 5)
  - Plan of Bay Ridge Parkway (New York), 1895 (Folder 4)
  - Charles River Reservation - Boston, Cambridge, Newton, and Watertown, 1895 (Folder 5)
  - Preliminary Plan for Proposed Improvement at the Southern End of Newport Harbor, Jan. 26, 1897 (Folder 3)
  - Preliminary Plan for the Improvement of Back Cove, Portland, Maine (Folder 1)
- Series V. Olmsted Brothers - Landscape Architects
  - General Plan for Keney Park, Hartford, Conn., Jan. 1898 (Folder 7)
  - Pope Park, Hartford, Conn. - General Plan, Dec. 1, 1898 (Folder 7)
  - Sketch Plan of Public Reservations Upon the Banks of the Neponset River, Boston, 1899 (Folder 5)
  - General Plan of Revere Beach Parkway, Boston, Nov. 30, 1899 (Folder 5)
  - Craig Colony, Sonyea, New York - General Plan, Dec. 1899 (Folder 4)
  - General Plan for the Subdivision of Fox Meadow - The Property of the Late Charles Butler Esq. Hartsdale, New York, Feb. 1900 (Folder 4)
  - Design map for Alta Vista - the Property of John B. McFerran Esq. Louisville, Kentucky, Mar. 1900 (Folder 2)
  - General Plan of Orange Park, 1900 (Folder x)
  - Mt. Holyoke College, South Hadley, Mass. - General Plan, 1900 (Folder 5)
  - Goodwin Park (Hartford, Conn.) - General Plan, 1900 (Folder 7)
  - General Plan for Portion of Roland Park, 1901 (Folder 1)
  - General Plan for Branch Brook Park - Newark, New Jersey, 1901 (Folder 3)
  - General Plan for Eagle Rock Reservation - Essex County, New Jersey, 1901 (Folder 3)
  - Plan for subdivision of property at Little Nahant (Boston) belonging to Sally M. Simmons, Feb. 1901 (Folder 5)
  - South Mountain Reservation Guide Map, Essex County, New Jersey, Mar. 1902 (Folder 3)
  - Revised Preliminary Plan for Grant Park, Chicago, Sept. 22, 1903 (Folder 8)
  - Palmer Park - Chicago, 1904 (Folder 8)
  - Russell Square - Chicago, 1904 (Folder 8)
  - Mark White Square, Chicago, 1904 (Folder 8)
  - Calumet Park, Chicago - Preliminary Plan for Park No. 11, Mar. 22, 1904 (Folder 8)
  - Preliminary Plan for Park No. 10 - Marquette Park, Chicago, Jan. 20, 1905 (Folder 8)
  - Duncan McDuffie Esq. - Berkeley, California - Planting Plan, Mar. 1914 (Folder 1)
  - General Map of the property of J. E. Aldred Esq., Glen Cove, Long Island, Feb. 17, 1916 (Folder 4)
  - Grading Plans for house and gardens. Mr. J. D. Aldred, Glen Cove, Long Island, Nov. 9, 1916 (Folder 4)
  - Meadow Park (Lynn, Mass.) - Preliminary Plan for Development, June 23, 1920 (Folder 5)
  - Mr. Loren D. Towle, Newton, Mass. - Planting Plan, Aug. 1, 1920 (Folder 5)
  - Mr. C. E. Steffey, Hills and Dales, Montgomery Co. Ohio Planting Plan, Jan. 29, 1921 (Folder 2)
  - Mr. Loren D. Towle, Newton, Mass. - Planting for Wall Garden, Mar. 24, 1921 (Folder 5)
  - Mr. Wilfred Ward, Westerly, Rhode Island Planting Plan, Apr. 9, 1921 (Folder 3)
  - General Plan for the Catholic University of America - Washington, D.C., Apr. 1, 1922 (Folder 1)
  - Memorial Park, Jacksonville, Florida - Planting Plan, July 10, 1922 (Folder 1)
  - Mr. E. Richard Meinig, Wyomissing, Pennsylvania - Planting Plan for Area East of Shelter, Aug. 28, 1922 (Folder 6)
  - Mr. J. E. Aldred, Glen Cove, Long Island - Planting Plan for Center Panel in Vegetable Garden, Oct. 26, 1922 (Folder 4)
  - F. M. Kirby Park - Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania - Planting Plan for Region About Fieldhouse at Childrens Playground, Dec. 1922 (Folder 6)
  - Southern Parkway (including what was once the "Speedway") Planting Plan, Newark, New Jersey, Jan. 10, 1923 (Folder 3)
  - Jackson Heights Gardens Apartments, Inc. Elmhurst, Long Island, New York Planting Plan for Garden Court (negative photostat), Jan. 22, 1923 (Folder 4)
  - Mr. George F. Baker, Jr. Glen Cove, Long Island, New York - Grading Plan, June 19, 1923 (Folder 4)
  - Preliminary Plan for Chickasaw Park, Louisville, Kentucky, Dec. 1923 (Folder 2)
  - Planting Plan for garden, Henry W. DeForest, Cold Springs Harbor, L.I., N.Y., June 1909 (Folder 4)
  - Planting Plan, Taft School, Watertown, Connecticut, April 1914 (Folder 7)
  - Planting Plan for Extension, Henry W. DeForest, Cold Springs Harbor, L.I., N.Y., Dec. 1914 (Folder 4)
  - Planting Plans for Flower Garden, J. E. Aldred, Glen Cove, L.I., N.Y., Feb. 1917 (Folder 4)
  - Planting Plan, Kiernan Burial Plot, Green Bay, Wisconsin, Oct. 1918 (Folder 1)
  - Planting Plan for Shrub Garden, Mr. Loren D. Towle, Newton, Mass., Aug. 1920 (Folder 5)
  - Patio Planting Plan, Edward W. Bok, Philadelphia, July 1922 (Folder 6)
  - Planting Plan for the Flower Garden, James A. Burden, Sussex, N.Y., Jan. 1923 (Folder 4)
  - Planting for Cut Flower Garden, S. Z. Mitchell, Brookville, N.Y., Apr. 1923 (Folder 4)
- Olmsted, Vaux, Co.Plan of Prospect Park, Brooklyn, reprinted 1901 (Folder 4)
- Series VI. Oversize Drawings
  - Warinanco Park, Elizabeth, NJ, D-1
  - Garden Plan, H. W. DeForest, Cold Spring Harbor, L.I., N.Y., D-2
  - Aldred Garden Plan, Glen Cove, L.I., N.Y., D-3
  - Garden Plan, H. W. DeForest, Cold Spring Harbor, L.I., N.Y., D-4
- Series VII. Pamphlets
  - Frederick Law Olmsted photograph 1905 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Mountain Lake Sanctuary, Florida 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The White House Gardens and Grounds [2000] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Preliminary Report in Regard to a Plan of Public Pleasure Grounds of the City of San Francisco 1866 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Observations of the Progress of Improvements in Street Plans with Special Reference to the Park-Way Proposed to be Laid Out in Brooklyn 1868 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Plan of Recreation Grounds for the city of Pawtucket (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Observations of the Treatment of Public Plantations More Especially Relating to the Use of the Axe 1889 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Landscape Problems in the Improvement of Spot Pond Reservoir, Metropolitan Water Works (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Improvement of the City of Detroit 1905 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Improvement of Boulder Colorado (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The First Canadian Housing and Town Planning Congress 1912 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - City Planning. American Civic Association. Series II (4) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Town and City Planning 1916 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Report on the Physical Development of St. Paul’s School Concord, New Hampshire 1923 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - California State Park Survey (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Proposed Park Preservation (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The Proposed Everglades National Park (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Architecture and Design. Vol. 3(8) (Box 1, Folder 17)